



- Omar El Gabry
- 8 +Omar El Gabry
- Omar_ElGabry

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name	Omar El Gabry	
D.O.B	23 July 1993	
Web	codesnippets.omarelgabry.me	
Contact	+201006398635	
Email	omar.elgabry.93@gmail.com	

Hello! My Name is Omar, 22 years old, Software Engineering Student.

It's very interesting when your personality and experiences are made of bunch of things that has nothing to do with each other, in addition you master only few of them.

I like to write Code, My dream is to explore the world, and I used to listen to music & watch movies.

EDUCATION

High School	Valley Language School - Thanawaya Amma
College	Computer Science - Software Engineering
University	Ahram Canadian University



EXPERIENCE

Microsoft App Factory

Dec. 2014 - Feb 2015

Trainee at the Academic App Factory Program

A training that focuses on Building Windows Phone & Windows 8.1 Applications. My Application was a puzzle game called "50".

Microsoft Tech Club

Oct. 2014 - Feb 2015

Tech Club President at Ahram Canadian University

Presenting Microsoft on the Campus. Hosting and Organizing events. Facilitating in sessions and training.

Google Student Ambassador

Aug. 2014 - June 2015

Google Student Ambassador at MENA

Received 4-Days training at Jordon

Learn about innovative Google products and programs.

Planning and host events on the campus. Act as a campus contact for Google.

ACM | Cairo University

Jan. 2014 - Aug. 2014

Junior Trainee

Solving intensive, complex problems using C++ and Java. Online Judges: Codeforces, TopCoder, UVA, SPOJ, ACMICPC

AIESEC | 6th October

Jan. 2012 - Feb.2014

Vice-President & Organizing Committee President

2 Years in Leadership roles in the World's Largest Youth Organization.

Events Organizing

Organized and Participated in 40+ Events & Conferences

- **Event Management**
- Crisis Management
- Effective Communication

Promotion

Participated in 15+ Online & Offline Campaigns for promoting AIESEC Membership and International

Internships

- Market Research & Eval.
- Marketing & Selling skills
- Customer Relationship

HR

Planned and Organized 15+ recruitment for international internships. Facilitator/Trainer at 15+ Conferences & Sessions

- Recruitment and Allocation
- Presentation skills
- Training and

SCCI Student Organization | CU Techware Participant

Nov. 2011 - May 2012

A workshop concluded by a three days conference. The workshop spans eight to nine weeks period (once a week) to give the Participants the chance to digest information about the latest Technologies and how to build your own device.



Insights.py

github.com/ OmarElGabry/Insights.py A Python package for reading, storing, & analyzing data from Public Data APIs. It provides modules for reading & parsing data from URL, storing data using a wrapper for SQLite, and performing some statistics.

python

Cubes

github.com/ OmarElGabry/Cubes Implementation of interesting algorithms in C++ and their related problems on online Judges.



Design Patterns

github.com/ OmarElGabry/DesignPatterns Examples of Design Patterns in Java.

Patterns covered: Adapter, Decorator, Bridge, Strategy,
Dependency injection, Iterator, Observer, State, Factory, Singleton



miniPHP

github.com/ OmarElGabry/miniPHP A small, simple PHP MVC framework skeleton that encapsulates a lot of features surrounded with powerful security layers.



University Portal

Not Available

A University management system built to facilitate the communication between the students and the academic staff.



50

http://bit.ly/1laustP

A simple game, It's idea is based on the neurons network. It tries to improve the process of storing and retrieval of the information in your brain. It has 25+ levels & scoring system.



Code Snippets

codesnippets.omarelgabry.me

This is my blog, where I post code snippets, tutorials on various topics. Code Snippets is a repository of useful code snippets, tutorials, developer tools, libraries and plugins, and latest news.



Hashtegny

github.com/ OmarEIGabry/Hashtegny jQuery Plugin aggregates hashtags from different social media networks(Twitter, Instagram, Google+, VK). Posts are displayed in a unique, attractive, and animated layout.



Machine Learning

Programming Language

Al Course - ACU

This is a small project during my Artificial Intelligence course. A machine learning program that tries to identify the number on the image using algorithms prior feeding the system with some samples.



C# & XAML

Python 3

Java

C++

Concepts

Data Structures and Algorithms Requirements Enginnering Analysis and Design Software Testing Software Quality Assurance/Control Databases Web Security



Specialities

Hobbies

Software Development Web Development Programming



Knowledge

Psychology & Sociology Software Engineering Computer Organization Data Strcutures & Algo Marketing and Selling

Web Development

HTML/HTML5
CSS/CSS3
JavaScript
jQuery
Ajax
Node.js
PHP
SQL
XML

Development Environment(IDE)

Netbeans Eclipse Visual Studio



Version Control System

GitHub(@OmarElGabry)

Graphics & Design

Photoshop

